是时候把红色标记的数值在main activity里进行实现了
It's time to implement the red lines for the main activity. We
我们先实现其中一部分，这样你就知道如何操作了
can do one part together so that you get the hang of it.
首先我们先设置Forecast布局中的列表项
We begin by styling the list item Forecast Layout. The red line specifies
标记中说明了这个图片应该是32dp x 32dp的。
that the image should be 32 dp by 32 dp. We could hard
我们可以在代码中直接设置图片大小为32dp x 32dp，但是这个效果和
code the image view to be 32 by 32 dp, but it's actually
在布局中设置宽高为"wrap_content"是一样的
the same as leaving it as wrapped content for height and width. To
如果需要知道设置wrap_content时图标的大小是多少，我们可以打开
know what the icon size would be if we wrap content, we open
MDPI版本的资源图标，这里我们可以看到它的尺寸是
up the MDPI version of the icon and we do verify that it
32px x 32px(px指像素)。无论我们设置实际值还是
is 32 pixels by 32 pixels. Whether we hard code it
使用wrap_content, 从视觉上看，它都是一样的
or just add wrap content, visually, the imagine will still look
但是考虑到程序的灵活性
the same, but in the future it will be more flexible
我们可以设置wrap_content，使程序能够自适应图片尺寸
if we just specify wrap content in case the image size changes.
接下来我们来处理文字。在ice cream sandwich以及更高版本的android系统中
Next we style the text. On ice cream sandwich and above,
Roboto是默认字体。
Roboto is the default font for text views. It is created
它是针对UI的需要和对高分辨率显示屏的优化所定制的。
specifically to satisfy the requirements of UI and to optimize for
红色标记表明这里的字体是
high density screens. The red line indicates that the font family is
Roboto sans-serif-condensed，所以我们在代码里这样设置
Roboto sans serif condensed, so we add that to the
对于字体大小，如果在程序中包含太多不同大小的字体
code. On the topic of font sizes, having too many font
会使用户分不清楚程序的前后层次
sizes in your app can confuse your user about the visual
也会混淆主要内容和次要内容
hierarchy of your app, as to what's important and what's not
Android设置指南中推荐使用这四种尺寸来
important. The Android design guide recommends these four type sizes
保证平台和用户体验的一致性
for consistency with a platform and for user experience. In our
的程序中，我们统一使用标准的字体大小。当然了，有一些是
app, we stick to the standard type sizes. And that's an
刻意设置的大小，比如这个较大的温度值
intentional part of the design, such as the large temperature values.
所以这里红色标记说明了日期文本的大小为22sp
Hence, when the red line say that the date text
我们可以把代码中文本的尺寸设置为22sp
should be 22sp for font size, we could specify Android
但是Andorid所推荐的
text size to be 22sp, but the text appearance large
最大文本尺寸已经是22sp了。对了这里注意一下字体尺寸的
attribute already maps to that value. Note that the font
单位是sp而不是dips。SP代表scaled pixels
sizes are specified in S-P, not dips. S-P stands for
它参照当前设备系统字体大小的设置进行自动放大或者缩小
scaled pixels, so you can scale with the device font
在我们的程序中，我们把字体大小设置为textAppearanceLarge
size. In our app, we specify text appearance large and
和textAppearanceSmall。也就是分别设置了22sp和14sp
text appearance small, which will give up 22spand 14sp respectively.
默认字体颜色是黑色的，所以我们无需
The default font color is black, so we don't need to specify
再在我们的程序中指定字体颜色
the android text color attribute on our text views. Let's look at the
下面我们来看一下列表项中的间隔。列表项中有三个区域
spacing for the elements within the list item now. We have three children.
第一个区域有60dp宽，里面的图片是居中放置的。
The first one is 60 dp wide, with the image centered inside of
所以我们可以在imageView周围添加一个FrameLayout
it. So we can add a frame layout around the image view
然后把gravity属性设置为center。
and set the gravity to be center on the image, that way the
这样一来图片就会在父容器中自动居中。对于另外两列，我们不应该
image centers itself within the parent. For the other two columns, we shouldn't
设置这么高的dp值。因为这些布局不会随着设备而自动改变尺寸
hard code such high dp values. Because otherwise the layout won't scale across
我们使用linearLayout的weight属性
other devices. Instead, we can use linear layout weights, the weight of
这里的weight值为7，而这里是5。我们可以尝试不同的数值
seven here, and the weight of five. We just tried different values
知道这个效果接近这个真实值。
until we got approximately equal to these values. The trick in doing
这里处理红色标记的技巧在于你既需要满足视觉细节
red lines is that you want to match the visual specs, but
又需要保持代码的灵活性，
you also want to be flexible in the code, so that it
使程序能够运行在不同尺寸的屏幕上。这就是list_item_forecast布局
adapts to different screen sizes. And this is what the code looks
而实现代码。
like for the list_items_forecast layout. We
我们用到了一个横向对齐的linearLayout,
have a horizontal linear layout, containing
里面有一个包含ImageView的FrameLayout。然后还用到一个纵向对齐的
the frame layout with the image view. Then we have a vertical
LinearLayout，它的weight值为7。而另一个纵向对齐的LinearLayout的weight值
linear layout with weight seven. And then we have another vertical layout
为5。你可以从下面的连接中获得代码文件。
with weight five. We can check the link below for the full
当你完成后，程序就是介个样子滴。
code file. This is what is looks like when you're done. These
下面这些列表项已经搞定了，today项我们还没处理。
items looks polished, but we haven't gotten to the today item yet.